

)li Baxanda

Lead Cloud Engineer, London

Accomplished software engineer, supporting cloud, full-stack and DevOps experience. Previously with an academic background and focus on research, I now specialise in enabling enterprise Cloud solutions. With prolific experience across start ups and established corporations, I have fostered a committed DIY approach and a fair love of coffee.

oliver@baxandall.dev

+44 7564 912273



in linkedin.com/in/oliver-baxandall

EXPERIENCE

Infrastructure Lead TraingHub Group Limited

04/2024 - Present City of London a disruptive fintech, with the goal to create the world's leading financial markets analytics platform

Co-Founder, CSO **TangleSwap**

06/2021 - 04/2024 a multi-million \$ cross-chain DeFi protocol on Cardano and IOTA EVM

- AWS organisation and Google Admin setup to ensure best cybersecurity practices over the 6 developer team, abstracting and distributing responsibility by component.

- Designed serverless backend for splicing blockchain data to thousands of users in real time, taking advantage of ethers.js, subgraph and openapi, before React integration.
- Maintenance of a Cloud hosted architecture to facilitate global access to the platform via several decentralised apps: CLMM-based Swap & Liquidity Pools, Smart Concentrated Farms, and a tokenised Governance system.

Senior Cloud Engineer Garrison Technology Limited

08/2020 - 03/2024 Waterloo, London hardware-enforced secure remote browsing solutions for enterprise

Achievements/Tasks

- Lead Integration of system designs into automated cloud IaC solutions using AWS CDK. Including Lambda, ECS, VPC, CloudFormation, RDS, Kinesis, IAM, API Gateway.

- Feature ownership including SAML, Remote Session data collection, DynamoDB ORM and OTP libraries to queue buffered log streams into aggregated CloudWatch.
- Responsible for code reviews, story boarding features and distributing responsibility to developers, using tools such as Jira, Confluence, draw.io and Gitlab.

Distruptive Cyber Security Researcher BT Research and Innovation, Emerging Security Paradigms

06/2018 - 08/2020

- Blockchain analytics, incorporating Apache Spark machine learning and Scala to analyse and classify complex data sets, automated in Jupyter notebooks.
- Nova a polymorphic blockchain visualisation tool for forensics of blockchain applications previously incongruous structures. Express, Flask API and Postgres.
- Regularly lectured to High School and University schemes monthly. Topics include Distributed Systems and Computer Science basics, for small classes or year groups.
- Owner of patents encapsulating VR, continuous authentication, layer-mapping and machine-user display, contributing to the BT Security portfolio.

EDUCATION

BSc Natural Sciences - Computer Science and Economics Durham University - 1st Class Degree

09/2016 - 06/2019

Outcomes

- President of University Dodgeball Team, organising weekly competitive games.
- Winner of Most Ambitious Hack and Best Use of Google Cloud Platform at Durhack2019 for producing a automatic, parameter centric running router.
- Received the 2019 Natural Sciences award for Outstanding Achievement.

SKILLS



REPORTS

The Key Determinants in the Price of Bitcoin: a Story in Speculation (06/2017 - 07/2018)

Sponsored publication by the Laidlaw Scholarship

Connected social trend data with volatility, concluding valuation dependencies and vulnerabilities of Bitcoin, uniquely modelling the quantitative price movements.

Automated Assessment of Procedurally Generated Graphical Level Content (06/2017 - 04/2018)

Durham University

- Researching techniques for systematic random generation in C++ and Blueprint in the Unreal Engine.
- Spawns original material for game engines followed by an integrated AI for evaluating and altering the final userexperience or developer environment.

Simulation of Malware Propagation and Effects in Connected and Autonomous Vehicles (04/2020 - 08/2020)

ResiCAV Autonomous vehicle project with BT Research

- Mobius a layer-based mapping tool, originally used for simulation of malware in autonomous vehicles using SUMO. Applied to tracking COVID contacts and 5G mast arson investigations.
- Shortlisted for CogX 2020 AI Product of the Year and winner of E&T's Excellence in Cyber Security Award.

ACHIEVEMENTS

UK National Chess Finals (2006 - 2009) Shortlisted for UK Ninja Warrior (2017) Professional Stage Magician 2018-2020 Commissioned 3D-Printed Brain MRIs (2021)

INTERESTS

